She's more than a toy. She's family.
M3GAN is a science fiction, horror film directed by Gerard Johnstone.
A brilliant toy company roboticist uses artificial intelligence to develop M3GAN, a
life-like doll programmed to emotionally bond with her newly orphaned niece.
But when the doll's programming works too well, she becomes
overprotective of her new friend with terrifying results.
Gemma, played by Allison Williams.
Cady, played by Violet McGraw.
M3gan, played by Amie Donald.
M3gan (voice), played by Jenna Davis.
David, played by Ronny Chieng.
Cole, played by Brian Jordan Alvarez.
M3GAN (pronounced "Megan") is a 2022 American science fiction horror film with black comedy elements about an artificially
intelligent doll who develops self-awareness and becomes hostile toward anyone who comes between her and her human companion.
It was directed by Gerard Johnstone from a screenplay by Akela
Cooper, based on a story by Cooper and James Wan.
Allison Williams and Violet McGraw star, Amie Donald physically
portrays M3GAN, and Jenna Davis voices the character.
It is the first installment in the M3GAN franchise.
M3GAN premiered in Los Angeles on December 7, 2022, and Universal Pictures
theatrically released it in the United States on January 6, 2023.
The film grossed over $181 million worldwide against a budget of $12 million and received
generally positive reviews from critics, who praised its campy blend of horror and humor.
A sequel, M3GAN 2.0, was theatrically released in June 2025,
and a spin-off, SOULM8TE, is set to follow.
The film explores themes of android, artificial intelligence (a.i.),
killer robot, aunt niece relationship, evil doll.
The tone is dark and emotional and thought_provoking.